Hello friends, such accidents keep happening
when a vehicle is moving on the road, but
after an accident,
many people
make a lot of profit in getting the vehicle repaired, the tax on which is often reduced is a
loss, now what will happen to it,
what will people normally do, everyone will take a claim, they will take a
claim because we have got
this vehicle injured, so we do
n't have to pay them anything, but even then
you incur expenses, if we get this vehicle
repaired outside and get it repaired with our own money, will it be
made the same way as the
insurance people are making it or is there some difference between the two, I will
show you all these things in this video today and we have to repair this vehicle,
tell you, see how much damage has happened,
first the right rear door is completely
damaged, there will be a dent, there will be paint, you can
see this, secondly, the
crossing, it has completely shifted inside, it has settled, there will be a
dent and there will be paint, the
quarter panel part will also be
painted because if you see here, there will be
sliding, so now see that,
you don't know how much has been spent on the vehicle,
what have you incurred,  All we know is
that our car should be repaired and
you
should see it from the front and some people cannot even
recognize how this work has been done, so today I will
show you everything in detail, first we will go to the
authorized service
center and see the process
of insurance, if I get this car repaired without
insurance, then how much will it cost
me to get it repaired at the service center, thirdly,
if I get the same work done outside in front of my eyes,
how much difference will there be in the quality
and how much difference will there be in the tightness, I will
tell you everything, I will also tell you some things about the inside
which maybe some people might not pay attention, so let's go to the
service center and
see how much does this car cost,
now see, we are going to the service center,
we will ask the service center
how much is the cost, but when you get it done through insurance, they do
not tell you the cost,
they directly tell you that sir, your
cost will be a P chart, normally there is a cashless
policy in which you only have to pay the file
charge, the file charge is
around Rs. 1000, second thing you have to do is
NC i.e. No Claim
What is no claim bonus? Whenever you go to take
insurance next time,
you get a bonus. If you have
not taken any claim in the previous policy, then
it is called no claim bonus. That
no claim bonus is lost for you. You will
not get it next time and it should be approximately
Rs. 2000 to 2.5 thousand as per this car. If I take a rough catch in Rs. 2000, then
Rs. 2000 is spent and Rs. 1000,
that Rs. 3000. Secondly, when I give it to him for
insurance, then at least for
a week, they will take five
to six days. Now, in six days, without the car and
if I calculate it, in 6 days, if I take a
car on rent of a taxi, then
give me Rs. 1500, then if I
put it on the car, then I will have to pay Rs. 6000 there. Rs.
6000 and Rs. 3000-9000 are the expenses of
taking insurance. Now, when we  You will have to get it repaired yourself
without insurance, then
two things have come up, you should go to an authorized service center
or to a garage outside and get it repaired as per
your convenience, if you are going to an
authorized service center, we
take the estimate there and calculate the cost, I will
also tell you what are the methods of repairing it,
sir, when you
give it to the service center, then you cannot get it repaired in front of you,
you will have to leave the car there
and then you will be called after the car is ready, yes,
we will take it to Tata Motors workshop, it is
of the body shop only, so
now I have inspected it, I
told me about the casting, let me tell you,
look, the casting of the paint of this door is
Rs 7000, the
casting of the paint of this panel is Rs 4000 and the casting of this side
will be empty touching, that is
Rs 3000, that is Rs 15000, this is the casting of the paint
and apart from this, this door will need to be new, this
door costs Rs 10000, the sliding one is around Rs 600,
so it is okay  It is 10000, let's take it for Rs.
15000 and we added 25000 and this 625
600 and after adding a little tax I
think it will come down to
Rs. 26000. Okay, now
see what they are going to do with this door,
consider this one thing, you see, there is a complete dent, we will
date it, after denting it we will make it
proper, but the dent that has come in this door will
not be dated, this
entire piece will be changed, they say, if
its dating is not possible then it should
not have been done, but they will
paint it, they are saying, so by changing this piece
and depending on this, after finalizing this whole thing, they
take us Rs. 26000 to 27000,
I think it takes more time here, so
I said let's find out once
what the cost is outside,
yes and the second thing is important, time,
so they told that
look, they need one week, so to reduce it,
when the part is available,
in how many days the part comes, that is a different matter.  Text
I checked and found that the door is not available right now. It
may take a week to 10 days for it to arrive.
Total 17 days. 27000 rupees. This is their
casting. If you do it in cash, then
before proceeding further, I would like to tell you that the sponsor of this video is
X Tool. X Tool is a
company that makes diagnostic tools for
scanning the car. The device I have right now
is fully capable of programming the car,
plus scanning it. They make x2 such
devices which are known not only in India but
all over the world.
Because of the updates of x tool, x tool is
becoming the number one company. So if you
want to know more about it or if you want to do some
multiplication, you can buy x2. If you
want more information, then the
website is given in the description. You
can go there and check everything. Now let's move
ahead. Look at this five line here.
Last time I got its bumper repaired. The
video of the plastic is not good, then I will
give its link in the description.
Check it out. It will get
dented and painted. The stripe on the back of the
car has gone.
I have a Rakhi, I have a bandage, it's
a little broken but it will work
[Music]
What will it cost, how will it work, I will bring it then, I wo
n't leave it on time, if I leave it then I will leave it tomorrow morning,
if you tell me the exact cost then it
feels like I got an electric shock, what is this, it's
not electric when doing it in reverse, friend, I am doing the same thing, if you
apply it in reverse then you get an
electric shock, if you fill it then it will be heavy, see now it won't work Karan Bhai saheb, no it happens only once, that's called static charge, we people, you feel it in many things, sometimes while walking you get an electric shock, you must have felt it sometimes, so this
is the bandage, I will put this only, I have kept
everything else aside
and what will you do with it, will you give me the
car in the morning, by evening I will
print the car, by evening I will keep it
here,
okay, yes, there is something left,
tell me the same, if you had asked then I wouldn't want anything extra
[Music] [
Music] You will get the
car by 6:00 in the evening,
you will get the insurance claim by 6, even then the
matter is the same, but the car is on a weekly basis  If it remains
parked, then we thought that friend, do
not take a claim, let's take it
out, will you lift it completely, friend, you will
fill it completely, it does not mean ISP, it is not like that, you will have to
pay tax equal to 14 full,
right, so see, this is the
calculation, now see, the point is
simple, 15000 rupees for 15 days
of car, 2000 rupees are
lost to you, 1000 rupees of no claim bonus will be lost, 15, 17,
18000 rupees are being spent, according to us, when
we take insurance, we do
not have to pay anything to the insurance person, how do
you have to pay and the car has to be insured, when the
insurance is decreasing, you cannot see
how the reduction is happening, how it is not happening,
I had taken many good cars for
claim to get insurance,
now this part has been changed but
in actual that part has not been changed and many times the
car was parked for a long time, so its other parts
also got displaced, so it becomes a big
hassle to take an insurance claim, that is why
I  Claims for small things are
not delayed, I always try
not to take claims, as far as it is in my hands I do it
myself but still you people do
not have any such hesitation, you
can take insurance claim if you want but
when can you take insurance claim when the expense is so huge,
I have shown you, it was such a huge expense that it appears
that sir there will be no
expense, when you go to the service center then the
expense is 25 to 27000 rupees only for
paying them, whether you do it in cash or cashless, even then the
expense is the same, you
understand it from here, you understand it from there, if this work is done
outside then brother
how much money did the outside person ask for, he asked for ₹6000 for
doing the original work and secondly you
can do the work sitting in front of you here, so right now
I am not doing anything, I will get it done,
I will be free tomorrow or day after tomorrow,
what do you people suggest, should I do it outside
or should I do it at the service center,
whatever is your suggestion and
whatever is your logic behind it, please do write it completely  It will
go to the comment box and if you liked this video then please
like it, you will get it
in the next video
with some such interesting topic, thanks for watching.